Li Yan

Name: Li Yan Nationality: China

Specialty: Mobile/Web Developer

Languages: Chinese, English, Japanese, Russian

Contacts:

Brief Introduction:

I have a Bachelor degree in computer science and have more than 11 years of IT experience. I started programming using Python and PHP at the age of 11. From 2008, and also Android and iPhone development of 5 years. I have been developing with PHP frameworks and Django including PHP, Python and also HTML, Javascript and also Java, swift, objective-C.

Beside PHP and Python, I have also specialized in web development using MEAN stack(Mongodb, Expressjs, Angularjs or Angular 2++, Nodejs) or MERN stack. For the last 3 years, I have been developing hybrid applications type of Web + Mobile or Desktop + Mobile as well as standalone Android and iPhone Apps. I have been working for different companies such as Radiant Systems, MEMOS, Riganti, Dlubal, and ISOFT with different technologies as developer, team leader & project manager and now I am working as a full-time freelancer and project manager of co-workers.

2004 - 2009

Education:

China Lastelli North Oniversity,	2004 - 2009
Employment History:	
Web Framework	2008-2021
Python & Django, Flask	2010-2021
Android Programming	2014-2021
IOS programming	2016-2021
MEAN & MERN	2016-2021

Abilities:

■ Web Sites Development

China Fastern North University

- Mobile Apps Development
- SW System Design & Project Management

Technology Skill:

- Basic Programming Languages
 - ◆ Basic, Visual Basic, Pascal, Delphi, C/C++, Visual C++
 - ◆ C#, VB.NET
 - Java
 - ◆ PHP
 - Python
 - ◆ Ruby
 - ◆ HTML5, JavaScript
 - Prolog, LISP
- Website Technology
 - ◆ ASP.NET WebForms & MVC
 - Boilerplate framework
 - NopCommerce
 - ◆ PHP
 - Yii, Laravel, Codelgnitor
 - WordPress, Magento, OpenCart
 - ♦ Python Web Development
 - Django, Flask
 - bottle
 - Ruby on Rails
 - JavaScript
 - jQuery, BootStrap, ExtJS, knockoutJS, drundal, AngularJS, Webix
 - node.js as web server
 - MEAN stack (MongoDB, Express.js, AngularJS & Node.js)
 - Responsive Web Design using Bootstrap
 - ◆ Web API & RESTful Web Service
- Mobile App Technology
 - Android Development
 - ♦ iPhone Development
 - Windows Mobile Development
- DB Technology
 - ♦ MS SQL
 - ◆ MySQL
 - ◆ SQLite
 - ♦ MongoDB
 - ◆ PostgreSQL
- SW Project Design & Management Skill
 - Planning using MS Project

- ◆ Good skill of writing requirements, DB & SW Architecture Design
- ◆ Designing with Enterprise Architect, Sybase Power Designer

Development Achievements:

Desktop Applications Development

♦ POS system

As developer in development of large-scale distributed POS system for 1 year at Radiant Systems.

Technology: WinForms, .NET Remoting, DevExpress, MS SQL

♦ Funding system for African children

This is a ${\it C/S}$ application for managing of fund raising for African children.

Technology: WinForms, MS SQL

♦ Reporting component for architectural analysis SW of Dlubal

Dlubal is famous architectural analysis software. I was in charge of generating reports of architectural analysis of construction.

Technology: MFC, Reporting

♦ IS - "LorealOptimise"

L'Oreal does strategic allocation of their products to stores based on sales history and I took part in development of that Sales Strategy IS for English-branch of L'Oreal Company.

Technology: WPF, MS SQL, DevExpress

♦ Dosimeter Measurement IS

This project is for entering & managing of dosimeter measure values and generating reports based on them.

Technology: WPF, MS SQL, DevExpress, Crystal Report

♦ GiftCard Management System

GiftCard's register & management system by using barcodes.

Technology: WPF, MS SQL, DevExpress

SharePoint component for identification & versioning of Word documents

Component written in c# for helping identification and versioning of word documents stored in Sharepoint.

Technology: C#, Sharepoint, VBA

♦ E-mail filtering component for a Danish Company

This company wanted to filter incoming & outgoing emails by groups of recipient addresses.

Technology: C#, MS Exchange

◆ Auto-creation of Network Diagram in Visio

C# component for auto-creating of network diagrams in Visio from JSON input files for an American client.

Technology: C#, JSON, Visio

Back office application for a retail shop

A retail shop's back office application for sales statistics.

Technology: C#, EntityFramework, DevExpress, MS SQL

■ Web Site Development

♦ Consolidated Reporting web site for Canon

Web site for consolidated reporting from data of individual distributors and resellers of Canon.

Technology: ASP.NET, MS SQL, DevExpress

♦ E-shop of notebooks

The web site of selling notebooks for a medium size of company.

Technology: ASP.NET MVC, NopCommerce

♦ Hotel Booking System

The web site for a private accommodation agency located in Paris.

Technology: ASP.NET MVC, Boilerplate framework

♦ Public Task Management Web Site

This project is for hosting task management web site in public and serving it for multiple companies in different levels according to their licenses.

Technology: ASP.NET, MS SQL, DevExpress

♦ Interview Management System

Using this website, employers can manage & schedule interviews with candidates for jobs of their companies.

Technology: ASP.NET WebForms, MS SQL

♦ Mobile Sales Force Automation Solution

This system consists of mobile apps and central web portal. Mobile apps are for sellers and central web portal is for distributors and administrators to manage data and administer the whole system.

Technology: ASP.NET MVC, AngularJS, Xamarin, MS SQL, SQLite

♦ Knowledge Management System using Word Press

Using this system, employees can share and use knowledge easily. It is built by Word Press Custom themes and plugin.

◆ DMS site

This is the document management system for a private company. Users can upload, search (keyword & content search) and download documents.

Technology: PHP Yii, MySQL

Ordering System for restaurants

Customers can easily order their food through the website without going or calling to the restaurant. They can book the seats & food or order to deliver food to their places.

Technology: PHP Framework Laravel, MySQL

♦ Data Center Web Application

User can upload and share to other users, and download data from others. Also user can have his private data storage location.

Technology: PHP Framework CodeIgnitor, MySQL

Hybrid Applications Development

♦ Mobile Station Monitoring System using SMS

The project was to build a solid monitoring system of mobile stations in very remote and secluded places where only telecommunication is available.

Technology: C#, Android, iPhone, J2ME, Bluetooth, AtMega, MySQL

♦ Wireless Ordering System

The project was to build a wireless ordering system using Android devices with Wireless connection. The system consists of central communication server, manager's PC Application, waiters' Android Apps, Kitchen Printer.

Technology: C#, Android, ProtoBuffer, Network Printer, MS SQL, SQLite

♦ POS System for Foodstuff Factory

The integrated system of retail applications + central web site

Technology: WinForms, PHP, MS SQL, MySQL

English Learning System

This system consists of Learning App for mobiles and central web site.

Learners can download contents of learning from the server to their mobile devices and admin manages learning contents through the central web site.

Technology: PHP, Android, iPhone, MySQL